# Sankar S

UI Developer/Front End Developer

## **Contact Info**

#### **Address**

Bangalore, India 560034

#### **Phone**

+91 9688472518

#### E-mail

sssankarsam@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/sankar-ui-developer

#### Website

https://sankarsans.github.io/

## Skills

- HTML/HTML5
- CSS3/SASS/SCSS
- Angular, Angular Material
- JavaScript
- TypeScript, jQuery
- Bootstrap, CSS Flexbox
- REST API
- JSON, Chart.js, RxJS
- GitHub, Bitbucket
- JWT, Token-Based Authentications
- Azure
- SEO, Accessibility Testing
- MySql, Cosmos Db
- Figma, Zeplin, Photoshop
- Node.js
- Responsive Design, Web Animations

## **Summary & Objective**

I'm having **5+ years of experience** working in a corporate environment as a **Front-end and UI developer**. Strong technical skills in complex web app development including web-based applications. Experience in **system analysis, design, workflow architecture, development, testing, and maintenance** of web-based applications.

## **Work History**

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

- July 2021 - Current

Encora, Bangalore

• I use managed the front-end implementations of the new features. Will be ensuring clean code every time. Working with Angular, TypeScript, and JavaScript.

#### **UI Developer**

- April 2020 - July 2021

Testsigma, Bangalore

 Built highly functional web applications using JavaScript, TypeScript, MVC, Angular 2+, Docker, Tomcat, Apache Web Server, HTTP Server, HTML5, and SASS/SCSS by following the agile-sprint methodology.

#### Front End Developer

- November 2017 - March 2020

GoProtoz, Bangalore

• Coded using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Angular to develop features for both mobile and desktop platforms.

#### Web Designer

- April 2017 - November 2017

Spiderwebindia, Bangalore

• The primary role was to develop the pages and create components for new features of the application. Have learned more about SEO and the user accessibility process.

#### **Education Details**

# **B.E - Electronics & Communication Engineering** - 2017

K.S.Rangasamy College of Technology - Tiruchengode

## **Higher Secondary School (HSC)** - 2013

Sengunthar Higher Secondary School - Salem

#### Secondary School Leaving Certificate (SSLC) - 2011

Sengunthar Higher Secondary School - Salem

## **Projects**

https://app.testsigma.com/

https://sankar-covid-tracker.netlify.app/

https://sankar-shopping-demo.netlify.app/

https://sankar-weather-info.netlify.app/

https://sankar-web-streaming.netlify.app/

http://acmefacade.com/

http://aliantstudio.com/

https://navzakti.com/